Welcome back to Jupyter Lab, where I want to show you the assignment, the homework exercise for you
주피터 연구소에 잘 오셨습니다 첫 주 마지막 날의 숙제와 숙제를 보여드리겠습니다
for the end of week one, coming into the week one folder.
첫 주 폴더에 넣어주세요
And you'll see here week one exercise so you can see there's rather little here.
첫 번째 주에는 운동량이 거의 없었죠
There's a little framework to tell you what we're doing.
우리가 뭘 하는지 보여주는 프레임워크가 있어요
So the idea is for you to build a little tool that will be used by yourself as something that can be
여러분이 직접 도구를 만드세요 이 과정 동안 여러분의 가이드가
your guide during this course.
될 수 있도록요
It's going to be a tool which will be able to answer questions on code, on llms, on things that you
코드와 llms에 대한 질문에 답변을 해주는 도구가 될 겁니다 여러분이 마주치게 될 수 있는
might run into along the way and be your sidekick, your your customized copilot for this experience.
것들이요 조수가 될 수도 있고 여러분의 맞춤형 부조종사가 될 수도 있죠
And this is what it's going to do.
이렇게 하는 거예요
Uh, it's going to you're going to fill in some inputs.
입력값을 채울 수 있어요
You're going to you can just use these two constants we've got here.
여러분은 그냥 여기 있는 이 두 상수를 사용할 수 있어요
You're going to be using both GPT and open source llama running in llama on your computer, something
GPT와 오픈 소스 라마를 모두 사용할 겁니다 라마를 컴퓨터에서 실행하는 거죠 2주
which you're familiar with from our week two assignment or day two assignment.
차, 아니 2일 차 과제에서 익숙하셨을 텐데요
You'll put some code in here to set up your environment.
환경을 설정하기 위한 코드를 여기 Put이 되죠
And then this is where you will type the question that you want to ask your tutor, your personal private
그리고 여기서 개인 과외 선생님께 묻고 싶은 질문을 입력하세요
And in this case, I am asking it to explain what this code does and why.
이 경우 이 코드가 뭘 하고 왜 하는지 설명하도록 요청하고 있어요
And this again, is that line of code that we looked at a couple of times, which is has a few different
이건 우리가 몇 번 봤던 코드 줄입니다 몇 가지 다른 게 있죠
things going on there, and this is the better version of the code than the one I originally wrote.
이게 제가 원래 쓴 코드보다 나은 버전이에요
This is the version that I think it was.
이게 그 버전인 것 같아요
Yeah, it was GPT four with canvas that wrote this version of it.
네, GPT 4와 캔버스로 이런 버전을 만들었어요
So we will provide this, and then you will fill in this piece of code here, which will get GPT four
이걸 제공하고 이 코드를 채우면 GPT for 미니가 응답할
mini to answer.
거예요
And you should try and answer and have that response stream back and use markdown, uh, so that it
응답 스트림을 되돌려 받아 마크다운을 사용해야 합니다 그래야 완전히
appears in full glory.
멋지게 나타나죠
Uh, and then do the same thing again for llama 3.2 and see the answer there.
라마 3에서도 같은 걸 하고요 2번, 답이 저기 있네요
So this will need you to to write the code from scratch and sort of type it out.
그래서 처음부터 코드를 작성하고 타이핑을 해야 해요
And of course you should look back at the fragments of code that we came up with on the prior days and
물론 우리가 이전에 만들어낸 코드 조각들을 살펴봐야 합니다. 이것들을 구축하는데
used that to build this, and hopefully it will be something that will come reasonably naturally and
사용했던 것들이죠. 바라건대, 자연스럽게 만들어지고 익숙한 것에 익숙해지길
you'll be used to the familiar .0., blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
바라요. 0살요 어쩌고저쩌고, 어쩌고저쩌고예요
It's all going to be something that will be in your memory and you'll also be very comfortable, I hope,
전부 여러분 메모리에 남을 겁니다 또한 아주 편안한 사전 메시지
with creating the messages list of dictionaries, something that you're used to at this point.
목록을 만들 수 있길 바랍니다 현재로선 익숙하신 거죠
Um, and when you do that, you'll see what answer that you get for this.
get을 입력하면 어떤 답이 나올지 알 수 있어요
And it's actually a remarkably good answer.
사실 아주 훌륭한 대답이에요
Again, I think much better than I could do.
제 능력보다 훨씬 낫다고 생각해요
Uh, and it would be interesting to see whether you're also happy with the answer that you get from
비교적 아주 작은 축소 모델에서 얻은 답에도 만족하는지 확인하는
a minuscule model that is much, much smaller by comparison.
것도 흥미로울 것 같아요. Get it!
And see how you compare those two.
그 둘을 비교해 보세요
And then in the future, you'll be able to use this as a bit of a resource.
미래에는 비트를 리소스로 사용할 수 있을 거예요
And so I hope this this is useful for you.
그러니 이게 유용하길 바라요
And in fact, after week two, you might want to come back to this and add a user interface to it.
둘째 주가 지나면 여기로 돌아와 사용자 인터페이스를 추가하세요
So you could have like a little tool running on the side that would be uh, could be super handy.
옆에 작은 도구가 달려 있으면 아주 편리할 거예요
Uh, one also thing that you might do is that what I've done here is I've just put down the question
여러분이 하실 수 있는 또 한 가지는 제가 여기서 한 건 질문을 전역 변수로
as a global variable.
입력한 거죠 Put
You might instead want to see if you can think about a way that you could take that in as an input and
비트 대신에 이걸 입력으로 받아들이고 좀 더 동적으로 만들 방법을
be a bit more dynamic about this.
생각해 보세요
So it could just be a cell that you run, but maybe do that as a as a later improvement.
그냥 세포만 실행할 수도 있지만 나중에 개선할 수도 있죠
Now I've done this and the solution is sitting in this solutions folder, but I urge you not to look
이걸 해뒀는데 솔루션은 솔루션 폴더에 있어요 하지만 솔루션은 보지
at the solution.
마세요
Uh, not not unless you you find yourself feeling stuck.
답답한 기분이 들지 않는 한은 괜찮아요
There's nothing worse than feeling stuck.
막히는 것만큼 괴로운 건 없죠
If you do feel stuck, you could always try first asking ChatGPT or Claude for a nudge, but otherwise,
막막하시면 챗GPT나 클로드에게 먼저 연락해 보세요 그게 아니라면 제발
please, please, please reach out to me.
제게 연락하세요
There is no reason whatsoever to be stuck with this.
이 문제를 계속 안고 있을 이유가 없어요
It should be something that you that you're able to to get through.
Get it은 여러분이 극복할 수 있어야 해요
And I would love to help you with that.
나도 돕고 싶어요
Get you to a point when you have your own personal, technical and data science tutor to help you along
개인, 기술, 데이터, 과학 강사가 도와줄 수 있는 단계까지 get it
the way.
up
So, um, above all, be sure to have fun with this and I will see you back for the wrap up video for
그러니 무엇보다 즐겁게 작업하시길 바라요 1주 차 마무리 영상에서 다시 만나요